John Clarke Slater Papers 1908-1976 Mss.B.SL2p
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1908-1976; 45 lin. feet (Box 1-89)
  - Slater, John Clarke
    - Quantum theory of molecules and solids, 6 November 1972
    - Quantum physics in America between the Wars
    - Quantum physics in America between the Wars Galley
    - Quantum theory of molecules and solids. McGraw-Hill marketing survey
    - Recent advances in quantum chemistry and their applications to catalysis
    - Recent advances in theory of energy bands
    - Recent improvements in the muffin-tin method
    - Recent progress by the X-alpha method
    - Relation between the convalent and the ionic bonds
    - Relationship between physics department and laboratory of nuclear physics
    - Remarks on the overlapping sphere method for molecular orbitals
    - Reminiscences in the development of solid-state physics. Raytheon, 3 April 1962
    - Report to the president
    - Review of quantum theory of solids, by Kittel
    - Review of the energy band problem with recent results
    - Review of the "Fermi Surface."
    - Revised manuscript of talk for the Maryland meeting.
    - Role of solid-state physics in MIT, 1960
    - The SCF-X alpha cluster method for polyatomic molecules and solids
    - Schenectady - theories of ferromagnetism
    - Second report on the theory of the magnetron, 1940
    - Self-consisten field method for crystals
    - The self-consistent field for crystals. Galley proof
    - The self-consistent field for molecules and solids
    - Semi-classical theory of the electro-magnetic field
    - A slight modification of Löwdin's method
    - Solid-State and molecular physics
    - Solution of the space-charge equation for concentric cylindrical cathode and anode, with axial magnetic field
    - Speech for Bridgman Dinner, 11 January 1947
    - Speech for Rossi dinner, 11 March 1949
    - Statistical exchange and the Heisenberg exchange integral
    - Statistical exchange and the total energy of a crystal
    - Statistical mechanics of phase changes
    - Summary of current research support in molecular spectroscopy
    - Talk for Columbus meeting, March 1952
    - Talk on history of microwaves, for symposium dinner, 9 May 1967
    - Talk on solid-state physics for military conference, 15 November 1949
    - Talk on teaching, 21 September 1949
    - Talks at conferences, 1950; 1951
    - A theorem in the correspondence principle
    - Theoretical foundations of low-temperature physics
    - Theory of energy bands and Fermi surfaces in solids
    - Theory of molecular binding
    - Transition probabilities and fractional occupation numbers in atoms
    - Travel vouchers
    - Treatment of exchange in atomic, molecular and solid-state theory, 1970
    - Vector potential in the X-alpha method: Magnetostatics
    - Wave functions for impurity levels
    - Wave mechanics in the classical decade, 1923-1932
    - What the college expects of an elementary course in physics
    - X-alpha energy bands and localized excitations in solids: theory
  - Slater, John Rothwell
  - Slater, John Rothwell The Good Life, or the Best?
    - Rochester Forty Years Ago
    - This too will pass
    - To Helen
  - Slezak, Jane A
  - Slichter, Charles P
  - Sloan, Alfred P., Foundation
  - Smakula, Alexander
  - Smart, J Samuel
  - Smith, Alpheus W
  - Smith, Charles S
  - Smith, Darwin W
  - Smith, Evelyn J
  - Smith, Cyril Stanley
  - Smith, F Dow
  - Smith, Franklin C, Jr.
  - Smith, Gretchen
  - Smith, Kenneth
  - Smith, Paul L
  - Smith, Robert Allan
  - Smith, T
  - Smith, Veden H, Jr.
  - Smith, William V
  - Smith-Corona Marchant
  - Smoluchowski, R
  - Smyth, H D
  - Smythe, Mrs. Miriam Carlisle
  - Snelling and Snelling
  - Snipes, Raymond Fletcher
  - Snow, Sir Charles P
  - Snow, Edward C
  - Snyder, Joseph J
  - Snyder, Ralph
  - Sobczyk, Andrew
  - Soceial Security Administration
  - Société d'Electronique et d'Automatisme
  - Society of American Archivists
  - Socony Mobil Oil Company, Inc.
  - Soderberg, C Richard
  - Soffren, Mel
  - Soh, Hsin P
  - Sokolov, N D
  - Solid State Advisory Panel
  - Solid State and Molecular theory group
    - Interim distribution list
  - Solid State Physics Conference, Allerton Park, Ill., 1954
  - Solid State Sciences Advisory Panel
  - Solis State Sciences Panel
  - Somerset Hotel, Boston, Mass
  - Sommerfeld, A
  - Sondheimer, E H
  - Sopka, Mrs. Katherine J
  - Southern Pacific Steamship Lines
  - Southwest Florida Realty
  - Space Technology Laboratories
  - Spada, H N
  - Spaulding-Moss Company
  - Speakman, J C
  - Spedding, F H
  - Speel, Henry C
  - Sperry Microwave Electronics Company
  - Spicer, William E
  - Spicer, W M
  - Spinks, J W T
  - Springall, H D
  - Springer-Verlag
  - Sproull, R L
  - Spyros, Dennis D
  - Squire, Charles F
  - Stalnaker, John M
  - Standard Telecommunication Laboratories, Ltd.
  - Stanford Research Institute
  - Stanford University
  - Stangl Potteries
  - Starr, C
  - State Farm Insurance Companies
  - Statz, Hermann
  - Stegner, Wallace
  - Stein, Josef
  - Stephen, Michael J
  - Sterling, James
  - Sterling Committee Meeting, 27 May 1948
  - Stern, Frank
  - Stevens, Donald K
  - Stevens, Malcolm S
  - Stevens, Phyllis E
  - Stevens, Robert
  - Stevenson, Donald T
  - Stevenson, Frank R
  - Stever, H Guyford
  - Stewart, Ralph B
  - Stockbarger, Donald C
  - Stockholm. K. Vetenskapsakademien...
  - Stockmayer, Walter H
  - Stoicheff, B P
  - Stolzenburg, Klaus
  - Stone, A M
  - Stoner, Edward C
  - Stoner, Richard G
  - Storey, Marjorie
  - Stout, J W
  - Strain, Harold
  - Strandberg, M W P
  - Stratton, Julius A
  - Stratton, S W
  - Stratton, S. W., MIT President
  - Strauss, Herbert L
  - Street, J C
  - Street, O Dickinson
  - Strickler, S J
  - Strong, Robert L
  - Struik Defense Committee
  - Stuchlik, Kark
  - Stuckey, Galen D
  - Student Problems
  - Student report
    - Almy, Gerald M
    - Armstrong, A H
    - Crawford, T H
    - Gleason, Paul R
    - Grabau, Martin
    - Wang, S C
    - Zener, Clarence
  - Student research problems
  - Study program in biophysical science
  - Stuewer, Roger H
    - The Compton Effect
  - Stukel, Donald J
  - Suggested MIT Policy concerning a field station at Fort Devens for the Laboratory for Nuclear Science ane Engineering.
  - Suits, C G
  - Sumner, Frank H
  - Suoninen, Eero J
  - Supek, I
  - Superintendant of dormitories
  - Surface Science
  - Susich, George
  - Sutcliffe, Brian T
  - Swann, William Francis Gray
    - Significance of atomic entities in modern atomic structure
  - Swanson, Daniel C
  - Swart, L R
  - Swedish American Line
  - Swedish National Travel Office
  - Swihart, James C
  - Switendick, Alfred C
  - Symes, Ernest
  - Symposium on "New aspects of valence theory;" Brooklyn, 1955
  - Synge, John L
  - Szasz, Levente
  - Szent-Gyorgyi, Albert
  - Szigeti, B
  - Tagaki, Rütsu
  - Takagi, Yutaka
  - Takagi, Satio
  - Takeshita, Toshio
  - Takeuti, Yoshihisa
  - Talley, W K
  - Tanaka, Shuzo
  - Taouil, Riad A
  - Tate, John T
  - Taylor, George K
  - Taylor, Howard S
  - Taylor, Hugh S
  - Taylor, Lloyd W
  - Taylor, Randall
  - Taylor, Shirley S
  - Taylor, W H
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Ass'n of America
  - Teager, H M
  - The Tech
  - TECHNION - Israel Institute of Technology
  - Teeter, Charles E, Jr.
  - Teller, Edward
  - Tenth International Conference on the Physics of Semiconductors
  - ter Haar, D
  - Terra Chemicals, Inc.
  - Tessman, Jack R
  - Texas A and M Universtty
  - Texas Instruments Foundation
  - Thacher, Henry C
  - Theater Guild
  - Theoretica Chimica Acta
  - Thimann, Kenneth V
  - Third Canadian Symposium on Theoretical Chemistry
  - Thirring, Walter
  - Thirteenth Annual MIT Conference on Physical Electronics
  - Thomas, Barbara E
  - Thomas, Frank L
  - Thomas, Harry S
  - Thomas, J E, Jr.
  - Thomas, Jean
  - Thomas, L H
  - Thompson, Alberto
  - Thompson, Elizabeth, Science Fund
  - Thompson, Eric D
  - Thompson, J C
  - Thompson, James S
  - Thompson, N E
  - Thomson, Colin
  - Thomson, Sir George P
  - Thorson, Walter R
  - Thresher, B A
  - Tilley, William R
  - Tinkham, M
  - Tiselius, Arne
  - Tisza, Laszlo
  - Tobey, A R
  - Todd, John O
  - Tomita, K
  - Tong, B Y
  - Torrey, Volta
  - To'th, K Enare
  - Totter, Robert
  - Townes, Charles H
  - Toyozawa, Yutaka
  - Transportation Systems Center (U.S. Department of Transportation)
  - Travel materials
  - Travellers Insurance Company
  - Tredgold, R H
  - Trefftz, Eleanore
  - Treinin, A
  - Trickey, Samuel B
  - Trilling, George H
  - Tripp, John H
  - Trump, John G
  - Tryon, James L
  - Trytten, M H
  - Tsuya, Noboru
  - Turlington, Ralph, Insurance
  - Turnbull, David
  - Tucker, D S
  - Tucker, Ross F
  - Turner, Arthur Francis
  - Tuve, Merle A
  - Tycko, Daniel H
  - Tyler, John M
  - Tyszko
  - Uenaka, Sotare
  - Ufford, C W
  - Uhrig, R E
  - Umberger, J Q
  - Umeda, Kwai
  - Union Carbide Corporation
  - Union Internationale de Physique Pure et Appliquee
  - United Aircraft Research Laboratories
  - United Kingdom Atomic Energy Authority
  - United Nations... UNESCO Scientific Bureau
  - U. S. Air Force. Aerospace Research Laboratory
  - U. S. Air Force. Office of Aerospace Research
  - U.S. Air Force. Office of Scientific Research
  - U. S. Army. Advanced Research Projects Division
  - U. S. Army. Mathematics Research Center
  - U. S. Army. Research Office
  - U. S. Army. Signal Research and Development Laboratory
  - U. S. Atomic Energy Commission.
  - U. S. Collector of Internal Revenue
  - U. S. Department of Justice. Immigration and Naturalization Service
  - U. S. Department of State
  - U. S. Department of the Interior. Office of Education
  - U.S. Department of the Navy. Office of Naval Research
  - U. S. Director of Defense Research and Engineering
  - U. S. Government Printing Office
  - U. S. National Committee. International Union of Pure and Applied Physics
  - U. S. Naval Ordinance Laboratory
  - U. S. Navy
  - U. S. Navy Office of Naval Research
  - U. S. Selective Service System
  - University City Bank
  - University Club
  - University of Calcutta
  - University of California
  - University of Chicago
  - University of Dublin
  - University of Florida
    - Alumni Association (honoring membership)
      See oversized
    - Basic principles for a University computer system
    - Chemistry library
    - Computing center
    - Department of physics and astronomy
    - Division of sponsored research
    - International symposium on atomic, molecular and solid-state theory and quantum biology, 1968
    - Physical chemistry division
    - Physics Department
    - Quantum theory project
    - University senate
  - University of Georgia
  - University of Kentucky
  - University of Liverpool
    - Conference on dielectrics
  - University of Louisville
  - University of Miami. Center for theoretical studies
  - University of Michigan
    - Symposium on electronics
  - University of Missouri
  - University of Pennsylvania
  - University of Rochester
    - Alumni Fund
  - University of South Florida
  - University of Utah
  - University of Wisconsin
    - Conference on the applications of X-Ray spectroscopy to solid-state problems, 1950
  - University Travel Company
  - Unknown
  - Untermeyer, S
  - Uppsala University. Quantum Chemistry group
  - Urbach, Franz
  - Urbana-Lincoln Hotel
  - Urey, Harold C
  - Utilization of space
  - Uy, Joaquin
  - Uyeda, Ryozi
  - Vaciago, Alessandro
  - Valk, Gene E
  - Vallado, Anthony C
    - Survey of effects of radiation on materials
  - Vallerta, Manuel Sandoval
  - Valley, G. E.
    - Re: arrangements for Cosmic Ray laboratory
  - Van Atta, L C
  - Van de Graaff, Catherine
  - Van de Graaff, R J
  - Van den Bosch, J C
  - Van der Bek
  - Vanderlip, Frank A
  - Van der Pol, Balth
  - Van der Waals, J H
  - Van der Waerden, B L
  - Van Horn, E L
  - Van Hove, L
  - Van Kranendonk, J
  - Van Nostrand Company
  - Van Vleck, E B
  - Van Vleck, J H
  - Varrićak, Mrs. M
  - Vashishta, Priya
  - Vchiyamada, Hilda
  - Verdier, Peter H
  - Verzuh, F M
  - Victoria Palace Hotel
  - Vieweg, Friedr., & Sohn
  - Villars, D S
  - Villars, F
  - Vineyard, George H
  - Vinti, John P
  - Vita
  - Vogel, Henry E
  - Volkoff, G M
  - Volpe, John A
  - Volta, Federico Dalla
  - von Hippel, Arthur R
  - Vonsovsky, S V
  - Vranek, J F
  - W Inc.
  - Waber, James T
  - Wakeling, Patricia R
  - Wald, Edwin
  - Walker, D and M. Krook
  - Walker, E L
  - Walker, Robert H
  - Waller, Ivan
  - Wallis, W Allen
  - Walsh, J M
  - Wannier, G H
  - War Department, United States Engineer Office
  - Ward, R
  - Wardman Park Hotel
  - Warheit, I A
  - Warnecke, R
  - Warnow, Mrs. Joan Nelson
  - Warren, Bertram E
  - Warren, Senator
  - Warren, Shields
  - Washburne, Joseph S
  - Wasserman, Harry H
  - Watanabe, Takeshi
  - Waterman, A T
  - Watson, Betty
  - Watson, R E
  - Watson, Richard
  - Watson, William W
  - Waugh, John S
  - Wawzonek, Stanley
  - WBZ-TV
  - Webber, R P
  - Weber, Jacques
  - Webster, D L
  - Weger, M
  - Wei, L Y
  - Weigang, Oscar E, Jr.
  - Weinberg, A M
  - Weiner, Charles
  - Weingartner, Rudolph H
  - Weinstein, D H
  - Weiss, Peter
  - Weiss, Richard J
  - Weisskopf, Victor F
  - Weisskopf, Vicky
  - Welch, George T
  - Welch, Robert S., Foundation
  - Welsh, John
  - Welsh, John H
  - Wentworth, Ralph L
  - Wertz, John E
  - West, C D
  - Westerkamp, J F
  - Westinghouse Electric Corporation
  - Weymouth, John
  - Wheeler, John Archibald
  - Wheelon, O A
  - Wheland, G W
  - White, A H
  - White, Harrison C
  - White, James
  - Whitehead, M A
  - Whitehorne, W R
  - Whitelaw, Betty K
  - Whitmore, Frank C
  - Whitmore, M
  - Whitney, W R
  - Who Knows-and What
  - Who's Who
  - Who's Who in America
  - Who's Who in the world
  - Wichers, E.
    - Commission on atomic weights
  - Wicker, E E
  - Wickert, C J
  - Widom, Benjamin
  - Wiese, W L
  - Wiesner, Jerome B
  - Wiff, Donald R
  - Wigner, Eugene P
  - Wiley, John, & Sons, Inc.
  - Wilhelm, J O
  - Wilkes, Gordon B
  - Willey, William J
  - Williams, Arthur O
  - Williams, F H
  - Williams, Ferd E
  - Williams, Helen
  - Williams, John H
  - Williams, Robert S
  - Williams, Stationery Company
  - Williamson, R C
  - Willshaw, W E
  - Wilmsen, C W
  - Wilson, A J C
  - Wilson, Charles W, III
  - Wilson, E Bright
  - Wilson, E Bright, Jr.
  - Wilson, Edwin B
  - Wilson, Kenneth G
  - Wilson, Timothy M
  - Wimberley, Stanley E
  - Winans, J G
  - Wise, Alfred J
  - Wishart, A W
  - Witmer, Enos E
  - Witte, H
  - Wölfel, E
  - Wolf, A
  - Wohlfarth, E P
  - Wolfe, William
  - Wood, James L
  - Wood, John H
  - Wood, Elizabeth A
  - Wood, John H.
    - Wave functions for iron d band
  - Woodruff, Truman O
  - Woods, F S
  - Woodward, Burton M
  - Woodward, W M
  - Wooster, W A
  - World Travel Service (International)
  - World Who's Who
  - World Who's Who in Science
  - Wright, D A
  - Wright, Fred E
  - Wright, Louis E
  - Wulfman, Carl
  - Wybourne, B G
  - Wyckoff, R W G
  - Wyman, Jeffries
  - Wynne-Jones, W F K
  - Xerox corporation
  - Yamaka, Eliso
  - Yamashita, Jiro
  - Yang, Cary Y
    - Truncated atomic sphere model and overlapping sphere corrections in the SCF-X-alpha scattered wave method-
  - Yannoni, Nicholas F
  - Yaqub, Mohammed
  - Yarranton, Arthur
  - Yevick, George J
  - Yoshizumi, Hiroyuki
  - Yost, Charles F
  - Young, Francis A
  - Young, J A
  - Young, Lloyd A
  - Young, Louis H
  - Young, R L
  - Yourgrau, Wolfgang
  - Yu, Chung-Hsun
  - Yukawa, Hideki
  - Yutzis, A A
  - Zacharias, Jerrold R
  - Zachariasen, W H
  - Zachor, A S
  - Zahn, Charles T
  - Zener, Clarence
  - Zganjar, Edward
  - Ziman, John M
  - Zimmermann, William J
  - Zope, J K
  - Zornberg, Eric J
  - Zubon, Michael
  - Zwicky
- Series II. Notes and bound volumes, 1926-1970; 29 linear feet
  - Averbach, B.L. Investigation of the metal-ligand bond in enzymes and proteins. A proposal for research. MIT.
  - Barrett, C. S. Lattice constants of gallium, 1961.
  - Conference on molecular quantum mechanics, June 1959.
  - Connolly, John W. D. Quantum theory of biologically important molecules, 1971.
  - European colloquium on current trends in quantum chemistry, 1975.
  - Goodwin, H. M., and J. C. Slater. History of Massachusetts Institute of Technology physics department, 1965.
  - International summer institute in quantum chemistry, solid-state physics, and quantum biology, 1970 July-August.
  - Kanamori, Junjiro. Resonance orbital and pseudo-Greenian.
  - Lax, Melvin. Application of group theory to solid-state physics, 1960.
  - Löwdin, Per Olvo. Recent research in the Uppsala and Florida quantum theory projects, 1971.
  - MIT. Miscellaneous materials (chiefly exams), 1932-1938.
    - Physics Departmental History, 1930-1948.
    - Preliminary design report. A continuous quarter million Gauss magnet facility, 1958.
    - Proposal for an interdisciplinary laboratory for basic research, 1959.
    - Ditto, 1961.
      Three editions.
    - Proposal for a research program in the properties of materials at low temperature, 1958.
    - Proposal for a materials center, (1959?-)1960.
  - MITnology. Renewal proposal for advanced research projects, 1963-1964.
  - Pratt, George W., and Herbert J. Zeiger. Lecture notes on the magnetic properties of matter, 1956-1957.
  - Schrieffer, John Robert. Multiplet separations in 3p and 3d electron atoms, 1953.
  - Shankland, R. S. Introduction to the X-Ray papers. The collected works of Arthur H. Compton.
  - Slater, John Clarke. Abstract of book [autobiography].
    - Atoms and Spectra. Physics 216. Stanford., Summer 1926.
    - The barrier theory of the photoconductivity of lead sulphide.
    - Bell Telephone Laboratories. Memo for file: Department 1400., 1942-1943.
    - A comparison of several exchange potentials for electrons in the copper plus ion.
    - Crystal stability and the theory of ferroelectricity, 1959.
    - Crystals and atoms, 1953.
    - Cu+ X LSW. F(n) allowed > 1. Ef - 4.08ry.
    - The current state of solid-state and molecular theory, 1966.
    - Electrodynamics of ponderable bodies.
    - Electron theory. Physics 10. Harvard, 1926.
    - Electronic structure of atoms and molecules. Manuscript.
    - Electronic structure of atoms and molecules Copy 1.
    - Harvard optic notes, 1925-1930.
    - The Hellmann-Feynman and virial theorems in the X-alpha method. MS and galley.
    - The Hellmann-Feynman and virial theorems in the S-alpha method. MS and page proof.
    - Improvements in the "Muffin-tin" method.
    - Interaction of waves in crystals. Galley.
    - Interview
      (2 copies)
    - Introduction to chemical physics. (incomplete)
    - Introduction to theoretical physics; MS. (mimeographed), 1932.
  - Slater, John Clarke. Lecture notes: Harvard physics 7. Kinetic theory, 1924.
    (used as a basis for Introduction to chemical physics)
    - Lecture notes: Harvard Seminary notes on wave mechanics; Electricity and magnetism; wave mechanics, 1927. 1928.
    - Lecture notes; MIT.; (used as a basis for Introduction to chemical physics), 1934-5.
    - Lectures on the energy band theory of magnetism.
    - List of people, places, things, etc.
    - List of physicists., 1971.
    - Los Alamos Collaboration; Among the correspondence included in these breakdowns are: John H. Wood. David A. Liberman, S. J. Cho, Timothy M. Wilson, L. F. Mattheiss, Frank Herman, Joseph B. Mann, P. W. Anderson, R. K. Nesbet, Walter A. Harrison, P. Gombás, William E. Rudge, Peter De Cicco, Keith H. Johnson, J. R. Roesser, A. Michael Boring, Arthur H. Freeman, Edward A. Kmetko, Robert N. Euwema, John W. D. Connolly, Vedene H. Smith, Jr., James T. Waber, E. C. Snow, Ingvar Lindgren and Osvaldo Goscinski., Oct. 1967-July 1968: July-December 1968: November 1968-May 1969: May-August 1969: September 1969-May 1970: May-October 1970.
    - Magnetron theory, November 1940-August 1941.
    - MIT. Current and new programs for materials research, May 1956.
    - MIT. Examinations and problems, 1936-1964.
    - MIT. Examinations and problems, 1952-1964.
    - MIT. Proposal...chemical and sold-state physics, May 1959.
    - Memorandum concerning the future of the quantum theory project, 1969.
    - Miscellaneous notes.
    - Miscellaneous notes and problems, 1927.
    - Miscellaneous problems.
    - Miscellaneous problems and notes, 1927.
    - Miscellaneous problems, manuscripts, etc.
    - Modern physics. Physics 20. Stanford University., Summer 1926.
    - Modern studies of the crystalline state. Buffalo lectures, 1963.
    - Notebooks, 1942, 1944.
    - Optical transitions and the statistical exchange in crystals., 2 copies.
    - [Papers of ferroelectricity and ferromagnetism.] Incomplete.
    - A physicist of the lucky generation. Autobiography., 2 copies.
    - Physics "C" Harvard University., 1925.
    - Physics manuscript.
    - Power series methods for cellular calculations on atoms, molecules and solids.
    - Principles of thermodynamics. 850 Heat and thermodynamics.
    - Properties of matter 1931 (Basis for part of Introduction to Theoretical physics)
    - Proposal for a grant for a program of research in the field of chemistry and solid-state physics, 1959.
    - Proposal for a materials center at MITn, 1959.
    - Proposal - published and unpublished papers, June 1971-1972.
    - Proposal: research on solid-state and molecular theory, 1969.
    - Quantum theory of atomic structure. 6 copies: Manuscript: Copy 1, 2, 3 [vol. 1], 4 (incomplete), vol. 2 copy.
    - Quantum theory of matter. 3 copies. Revised edition: Page Proof (incomplete): 2nd edition page proof.
    - Quantum theory of molecules and solids. 34 copies: (2 copies); (2 copies); Bibliography; vol. 1 (8 copies), 2 copies of the manuscript, Copy 1, Copy 2, and copy with Appendix 12, copy 3, copy 4, copy 5; vol. 2 (5 copies), Manuscript, another manuscript, Incomplete copy, Copy 2, and Bibliography; vol. 4 (8 copies), Manuscript, Incomplete manuscript, Copy 2, another manuscript copy, Incomplete carbon copy, Page proof (incomplete), Page proof, and Bibliography and Index (galley); vol. 4 (8 copies), manuscript, manuscript (2 copies), manuscript, Bibliography copy 1, 2, 3, and 4., 1971 1972 1969 1970 1971
  - Slater, John Clarke. Quantum theory project; Contains correspondence, articles, Sanibel Island conference materials (U. of Fla.), etc., February-August 1970.
    - Research on solid-state and molecular theories, 4 June 1969.
    - Results of linear chain calculations.
    - Scientific notes, 1920-1923.
    - Scientific notes, 1924-1926.
    - Scientific notes, January 1932-September 1933.
    - Scientific notes; Cambridge-Copenhagen, (assembled, 1923-1924. 5 December 1968).
    - Scientific notes: Electrons in metals, September 1933-March 1934.
    - Scientific notes: Electrons in metals. Momentum Eigenfunctions, April 1934-June 1935.
    - Scientific notes. Energy bands of Cu, Ni. Ferromagnetism of Ni, June 1935-February 1936.
    - Scientific notes. Ferromagnetism-temperature dependence. Optical absorption by alkali halides, March-November 1936.
    - Scientific notes: Helium, 1927.
    - Scientific notes: Helium atoms. Atomic self-consistent fields, 1928.
    - Scientific notes: Leipzig. Cohesion in monovalent metals. Notes on Hartree's method, 1929.
    - Scientific notes: Molecular energy levels. Analytic atomic orbitals, July-December 1931.
    - Scientific notes: Molecules, shielding constants, polarizability, multiplets, directed valence, electron emission, Van der Waal's equation, 1930.
    - Scientific notes: Phase transactions KH2 PO4 NH7CC. Pressure effects on magnetism, August 1939-October 1940.
    - Scientific notes: Theory of complex strata. Optical property of metals, 1928-1929.
    - Scientific notes: Van der Waal's equation. Equivalent of state molecular orbitals, January-June 1931.